Summary

Passionate about robotics and self-driving technologies. Experienced with motion/path planning algorithms (A*, PRM, RRT*) and open-source libraries, including OMPL, ROS navigation stack, and Utexas-art-ros-pkg (Austin Robot Technology, 2007 DARPA Urban Challenge). Startup spirit and a creditable YC startup internship.

EDUCATION

University of South Carolina, Columbia, SC

Ph.D. Candidate, Computer Science Dec. 2015

University of New Mexico, Albuquerque, NM

M.S., Electrical Engineering Dec. 2009

China University of Geosciences, Wuhan, Hubei

B.S., Electrical Engineering June 2007

Work

Auro Robotics, Inc. (YCombinator S15), Sunnyvale, CA

EXPERIENCE

Robotics Engineer Intern

June 2015 – Aug. 2015

- Developed and tested motion planning algorithms for the self-driving shuttle
- Cooperated with the technical lead to implement a waypoint-following path planner
- Implemented an OMPL-based RRT* path planner using a costmap of perception
- Conducted autonomous drive tests of our autopilot software with the vehicle

RESEARCH

South Carolina Autonomous Robotics Research (SCARR) Lab, USC

Experience De

Decentralized Formation Algorithm for Multi-Robot Systems A

Aug. 2013 – Present

- Innovated a distributed formation algorithm for the multi-robot systems
- Promoted a provably-correct decentralized formation algorithm with time-bounded executions and optimized formation qualities
- Developed ROS-based software simulations with C++, Python, and Bash
- Designed and built a GUI with the GTK+ and the Boost libraries

SCARR Lab, USC

Planning Algorithm under Uncertainty

Aug. 2010 – May 2011

- Promoted a geometric algorithm for robot planning under uncertainty
- Accomplished the algorithm and simulations using C++
- Achieved the same level of performance as using the approach that computed the high-fidelity information states, but with a small fraction of the computational cost

Multi-Agent, Robotics, Hybrid, and Embedded Systems (MARHES) Lab, UNM

Multi-Robot Control Algorithm

Aug. 2009

- Implemented a cyclic pursuit algorithm for nonholonomic vehicles with MATLAB/C++
- Implemented simulations with Player/Gazebo

Language &

C/C++, Python, Ruby, Java, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, LTEX

Tools

ROS, Git, CMake, OMPL, OpenCV, Bootstrap, Boost

Honors & Awards

Member of Upsilon Pi Epsilon NSF Student Travel Grant Award

May 2014